[Music]
world msme day is celebrated annually on
June 27th and this was instated by the
United Nations in the United Nations
General Assembly now this day seeks to
raise awareness about the potential of
MSM to contribute towards the
sustainable development of the globe in
fact in India also msme day is
celebrated on the very same day to know
more about the importance of msmes to
the Indian economy and how can they make
the most of the opportunities on hand
welcome to a special show ICI Lombard
General Insurance presents celebrating
India's msmes partnered by ET now where
I'm in conversation with the chief of
technology and health underwriting and
claims at ICI General Insurance Girish
nyak on this very special show thank you
Girish for joining me here my first
question to you you know According to
some statistics there are over 63
million msmes spread across India and
they contribute nearly 40% to India's
exports they contribute about
6.11% to the country's GDP from the
manufacturing sector and 24.6 3% to the
GDP from the services sector so Gish is
this the best time to be an msme in
India wellit uh I think it's the best
time to be in India and definitely the
best time to be in msme in India as you
know uh the Indian economy is going to
be one of the fastest growing econom
large economies uh at least projected
for next three years in spite of all the
global uncertainty that you see uh the
strength of domestic demand has kept our
economy uh very resilient and has been a
key Catalyst for the growth look around
you the signs of this activity all
around I mean you have the increasing
GST collections you have the increasing
uh volumes of the eBay bills you have
the increased electronic to every
everywhere around you see signs of how
the domestic uh demand uh is really uh
supporting the economy and you see
various other indicators Tractor Sales
Auto Sales uh your credit growth
everything is pointing to a uh a
significant momentum in the economy all
this is kind of underpinned by the
entire digital public infrastructure
that uh has been set up in the country
in the last few years and uh that's
really powering a lot of uh growth at a
grassroot treel a lot of government
initiatives uh over the last few years
you can see that while uh they are at a
larger corporate level but how they
impact the msmes as well the make in
India digital India startup India lot of
these initiatives and uh while you we
might say lot of make in India is for
large uh Enterprises there's also a huge
trickle down every time a large
Enterprise sets up uh in India you have
a lot of msmes getting up all around it
right so there's a there's a huge
Network effect that kind of uh plays out
and as uh you can see that over the last
few years with the pla scheme uh there
is a lot of company setting up
manufacturing facilities in India
attracting Investments you we promoting
exports all this is providing ample
scope for msmes to kind of uh really
grow and prosper uh startup India
initiative uh lot of schemes tax
benefits funding opportunity the mudra
uh loan
scheme I mean government has really been
uh also very vocal about the fact that
msmes are the uh heart of the
country's manufacturing infrastructure
and they are putting all the necessary
uh uh levers in place to help them grow
and flourish that's so important what
you mentioned Gish because yes the
government schemes are also of great
help plus what the last point that you
made you know about how technology it's
and and we've also been discussing this
on the channel that it's no longer that
they're local they are now global they
could be from any small town in the
Interiors of India but their products
their services are available around the
globe which is helping them so much uh
but you know Girish moving on in our
conversation what are some of the key
events or elements that you feel are
helping msmes in India to go for growth
I think first and foremost uh like I
said earlier over the last few years we
can see that the whole digital public
infrastructure that has come up I mean
that's a significant I mean we don't
realize how important it is but that
really forms the basis of like you said
allowing msmes to expand their reach
beyond what their local uh sphere of
influence is u also uh in terms of uh
ability to compete
right one of the big challenges MSM had
earlier versus larger corporates with
larger corporates could spend so much on
technology which uh msme could not
afford to now with cloud computing
available the best and most modern
technology resources are available to
the msme for uh as a the pay as you go
model so they don't have to make upfront
investments in technology and they can
have the same technology sometimes even
better than large corporates can have
and that uh is a significant growth
booster uh you have a lot of e
e-commerce plan over the last three four
years uh the spread of e-commerce
platforms which allow msmes to kind of
uh in a very effective and affordable
way reach a larger much larger customer
base than uh what they could do earlier
and that has had a significant impact on
the growth uh potential that msmes today
have uh leveraging both the digital
public infrastructure as well as the uh
e-commerce
platforms along the period you also seen
uh government as well as corporates uh
invest a lot in skill development for uh
msmes and this is at a very Grassroots
level so that's also creating a skilled
Workforce for the msmes to uh absorb and
creating job opportunities for the uh
Youth of the country also I mean um in
terms of finan
like I spoke about the uh mudra loan
scheme has made available a lot of uh
financing options for msmes which
earlier was uh could have been a
constraint uh uh in a way absolutely and
uh you know that's a very I just want to
add to one point that you made there
Girish you know about upskilling and
exactly the part that you said about
technology technology is also helping uh
smmes up skill so easily because it's
available
on the mobiles people the the employees
even the management of msmes are able to
uh access so much data so much
information online which just helps them
uh get better and better in every day
but I also know Girish that um at IC
Lombard General Insurance the insurance
business uh it's it's I mean smmes are
very important to the company as a whole
so how do you see the insurance business
as part of the overall business of I C
Lombard General Insurance definitely is
a very very key component of our
business and we have been having a very
very sharp focus on this sector uh for
many years now I mean uh we are one of
the first private sector uh insurers to
significantly focus on this uh segment
we earlier the segment was largely
served
through the PSU Insurance primarily
because uh none of the private insurers
had large distribution footprint across
uh
different smaller towns and villages in
India where uh the msmes are largely
existing and this was covered by the PSU
insurance so they had Direct access and
they used to be able to Service uh msmes
but when uh I a Lombard approached this
problem of how do we reach msmes we used
a lot of Technology options to make uh
their whole
in Insurance process very easy fast
convenient and that helped us gain a
significant penetration into this market
and also help service this uh segment in
a much better way than they were hither
to being serviced so we we take a pride
in being a Pioneer in uh msme insurance
and that to technology enabled uh msme
Insurance we've been uh celebrating
International msme Day uh and launching
tailored Solutions for msmes last year
on International msme day we had a
complete uh 36 360 degree uh Salam msme
campaign uh to celebrate the uh spirit
indominable Spirit of uh the micro small
and medium Enterprise uh Enterprises and
the entrepreneurs and when we doing this
campaign also last year we had
collaborated with several Chambers and
associations to uh talk to them about
our perspective
uh and how it's uh Insurance should form
a critical part of risk management for
msmes because that's something that uh
we do find as a gap in their uh risk
management practice and uh it's
something that we kind of uh work with
the uh Chambers and associations to get
this message across to them and uh also
I mean as a company we have the whole
range of product uh options available
for or msmes who uh need risk coverage
be it uh normal fire and uh fire
insurance or Marine Insurance liability
insurance uh engineering uh Insurance
even uh Group Medical uh insurance for
their uh employees U and even uh newer
products like cyber Insurance cyber
security insurance so we have the whole
range of products not only that uh we
have been the first and I think we are
probably the only uh insurer to sellme
products online digitally uh through a
website so we have uh ww. sm. icar.com
which uh is our portal for smmes where
uh can owner or the finance person from
can come and buy insurance required to
uh their requirements purely from our uh
website and this is very very convenient
for uh smmes because they don't have to
go through un we try to make the
products as simple as possible which
kind of covers their
[Music]
need you know you spoke about some very
unique offerings like you spoke about
cyber security risk uh cover the these
are relatively new products so in the
largest scheme of things how important
do you feel risk management is today and
why do you think it is something that
msmes need to focus on see risk
management for any corporate is a very
essential part of their uh strategy uh
what we do find is lot of msmes uh do
not have that very strong focus on risk
man so we work with them uh we have a
lot of risk management practices which
we use with our large corporate clients
we are able to bring the same thing down
to uh msmes and help them with setting
up their own risk management practices
uh that because risk management From
msme perspective versus a large
corporate perspective is slightly
different right uh you have various
types of risk you can face you have
Financial Risk you have uh you have your
uh Market risk you have operational risk
when uh a large corporate faces a event
a risk event uh say a financial downturn
the the financial buffer available or
cushion available large corporate is far
better than with a MSN similarly a
catastrophic event like a flood or
a cyclone large corporate will also face
damage a small corporate also msme will
also face a damage but the ability of uh
the large corporate to manage after that
damage is far better because they have
lot more working capital lines lot more
facilities and a larger diverse business
but msmes uh often their only source of
income gets disrupted completely by uh
these kind of events so the risk
management needs to be far uh better and
far uh tighter at the msme level plus
maybe positional Solutions also uh in
fact I talked about product issuance uh
technologically we also uh help msmes by
uh turning around claims much faster so
for example uh for typically MSM claims
are smaller because size of operation is
smaller so for property and Marine
claims uh which are less than five lakhs
uh we we have a we have a current this
going on where we say that we will uh
give an offer of a settlement within 10
days of intimation of claim and that's
okay that's really helps the msmes I
mean uh get back on their feet as fast
as because if your damage is uh within
five lakhs and I can give the claim uh
disbursement within 10 days so there
minimum downtime minimum time lost and
Ms can get back on their uh on the
business very fast yes and absolutely
for doing all this we do have a lot of
stateof AIML systems big data analytics
which help us in Faster distance make
uh on processing the claims but finally
all this has to be the front end of
helping uh the customer uh recover
faster U get back on their feet and be
able to do business uh much smoother
today's world one is really fast
changing two after the pandemic things
have just drastically changed so what
are some of the major risks faced by
msmes today uh like I said Financial
Risk is always uh a very CR key risk
that MSM face this could be to the cash
flow the debt management liquidity uh
and often it could be for no point fault
of theirs right I mean if they uh
customers don't pay on time if they have
a cash flow Downstream that just flows
back to the msmes they are the first to
get hit uh Market risks uh definitely
change in customer preferences market
demand could be a this during the
pandemic we could see operational risk
like supply chain uh disruptions were a
significant uh risk and there could be U
regulator and compliance risks as well
because uh now with increasingly see one
aspect of the digital public
infrastructure and a very well oiled GST
and uh uh taxation system coming in is a
lot of compliance uh requirements also
which get uh come in place and uh again
with msmes uh there's a risk that some
of these uh nuances of compliance may
not uh be met and that could be a
compliance risk one major risk uh that
is developing uh and we see this uh
quite regular is the cyber security risk
which again understanding of this risk
and the extent of damage it can do uh a
risk event in this uh segment can do is
something that people do not not really
uh understand or appreciate and uh as in
when we becoming more digital we are
using uh uh digital means to sell our
product as well as manage our uh
payments cash and everything it's it
really becomes uh a significant risk uh
which was not there perhaps five years
ago when M MSM are not digital if you're
not connected if you're not digital you
don't face a cyber security risk right
so
uh the flip side of being digital is
that there is an increased uh cyber
security risk but of course there are
ways and means to manage this risk and
uh insure against it so uh a
whole spectrum of risks but I think what
is important uh like I mentioned before
is to have the appropriate risk
management practices in place so that uh
uh you have the uh methods to uh
mitigate the risk or manage it if a risk
event occurs much better and of course
insuring against the risks is important
and understanding what the right amount
of insurance that you need to have to uh
manage this is also uh important and
it's not only uh risk at say um the uh
the msme level it's also risk to the
employees right so uh you have uh group
medical insurance for the employees
that's that's important right you
have workman's compensation policies for
employees because
uh very Lim limited staff they could
have an accident or there should be a
way to kind of manage that uh this so
for
example uh a few months back we had a
case where in msme there was an accident
on a construction site three workers uh
were injured luckily because they were
covered by our policy we could take them
to a hospital very quickly where we
could uh and that did help saving their
lives and also for the two months that
took to recover uh we could pay their uh
salaries for them that's that's
uh again from employee point of view but
yes because the msme had taken a cover
for that then they are able to give a
kind of uh cover for the employees uh
for for any risk events as well so uh
risks not only at
the organization level but managing
risks for their employees as well to the
extent that they can Gish those are very
interesting uh points that you raised
but you know you've already told us
about many of the key initiatives and
offerings of IC Lombard but can you tell
us some more and especially anything
that you're launching uh this world msme
day this year for uh msme day uh We've
uh had we've enrolled our wom msme
agents uh for exclusive tailor made
program on Insurance and financial
literacy we found that that was a gap
area and uh we thought we should address
it and this is very much in line with
the company's vision for creating a very
inclusive and dver diverse uh not only
uh employee Force but uh also with our
agents and other stakeholders as well
and furthermore uh for this msme day uh
we also launch a special product
coinciding uh with the event that is
called suraka kage which is a kind of
bundled umbrella umbrella product fores
uh which has multiple offerings and
covers all under one single policy
single window so that they don't have to
kind of piece together multiple
Solutions and try to address the various
risks that they face so uh we do uh try
and come out with something which uh
understands uh the pain area of uh the
msme customers and try and address that
specifically through uh tailored and
custom generated product offerings
fantastic well thank you so much Girish
for sharing all the great work that IC
Lombard is doing as well as throwing
light on the larger msme space in India
on this very special episode thanks once
again Gish and thank you to the viewers
for having tuned in to watch this
special episode of ICI Lombard General
Insurance presents celebrating India's
msmes partnered by ET now thank you so
much for watching watching
[Music]